Huh?
Am I... in water?
What are these lights?
A giant fish?!
No... a dragon!
Sera....
I am glad I chose you.
What?
Wait! What do you mean by—
It was a dream?
But why...?
How could a dragon talk?
And such a massive creature...
I've never seen or heard
of anything like it.
Did the Morisuberi we hunted show
up in my dreams, or something?
Get off...
Illdoren, you're gonna
squeeze my guts out...
L-Lady Vyufmec?!
The Warrior Princess and the Barbaric King
There are elves and dwarves
from out of a fairy tale,
along with some
menacing-looking living plants...
You are so obnoxious.
Wh-Why am I being forced to deal with
barbarians and inhuman creatures?!
I already told you; today we're
performing the great cleansing ritual.
Which is why the five tribes have
gathered so early in the morning.
E-Even, so, how do you expect me to accept
something so egregiously fantastical?!
Y'know, in the short time I've known
you, it's clear how fanatical you are...
But do you really think that the
only things that exist in this world
are the things that you
personally find believable?
Hey, the gang's all here.
Saint Wysteresia!
You're responsible for
the blight, this time.
So you're going to participate in our
tradition of the great cleansing.
B-But...
Cleansed though you may be,
it's important you personally
see the results of your actions.
Cleansed?
She doesn't even realize it...
Say that again, elf?!
What name did your parents give you?
You want my name?! What for?!
Let's just hear it.
Well, I got the surname
of Malcius from the abbot,
seven years ago when I
became a retinue priest...
Wait.
What did they call me at
the orphanage again...?
I know that becoming a retinue
priest at 16 was unprecedented...
But prior to that? Sixteen years...
You don't remember any of it?!
And 16 years would be
the majority of your life!
Th-That can't be right!
I can remember six years
ago... seven years ago...
Eight years ago... nothing?
Nothing, nothing, nothing?!
Whoa, Malcius!
It's an effect of the blight.
It's honestly a miracle she
survived in the first place.
True. You could say that losing
her memories is a small price.
Though I doubt she'd agree.
This might be insensitive,
but maybe forgetting about the
memories of being a slave to religion
would be better for her...
Wha?!
Wh-Wh-What did you just say?
You think I'd be better off forgetting
my devotion to the Lord?!
H-How dare you?!
Then try and remember something.
Assuming there were any thoughts
in your head to remember.
Y-Y-You just keep running
your mouth, you little wench!
I only stated the truth,
you freckled four-eyes!
My a-a-appearance has nothing
to do with my religion!
They met a few days ago and
look how they get along...
Hard to say if they're compatible, or not.
Shouldn't we do something?
I doubt it'll escalate
into anything dangerous.
And if it does, I'll stop them.
Yeah, fight, fight!
You start a fight, and are
already on the ground?
You were the one who was
mocking me, barbarian girl!
Don't take a retinue priest with the
E-E-Eastern Expedition forces lightly!
All that marching has made me fit!
Ow! Ow!
You might've been able
to get the drop on me,
but if you really think I'm
better off without my memories,
then how about this, little barbarian?
I might hate what the
Order of Commoneras stands for,
but I did receive some
charity from them once...
I forgot to mention this earlier,
but did you know that this
barbarian-styled girl is actually—
She's got her.
Bar...bar...ian...
We have a winner!
I suppose I'll carry Malcius...
Why don't the three of you
run down to the river, then?
There's still time before
the great cleansing.
It'll be a good chance to get in
the water and clean up a little.
A good suggestion. A wash before
the ritual would do you well.
B-But...
The preparations will go
just fine without you three.
I mean, it's not like
you have anything to do.
Don't feel bad!
I'm going to spend the ritual relaxing
at my nephew's house, anyway.
I'm too old for this shit!
Resia...
You heard her, Cersei.
See them to the river.
Right.
I'm sure you noticed,
from what this fanatic nearly said...
And it's true. I am from Illdoren.
I was part of the Eastern
Cultivation Corps, six years ago.
I thought as much.
Your disdain for nobles, and the fact that
you called me a knight instead of
a warrior had caught my notice.
That said, I'd imagine learning
how to help equip armor
didn't come from being in
the Cultivation Corp...
I'd ask you not to pry any further.
That country isn't my home anymore.
I am Cersei, Master Veor's attendant,
and these lands are where I belong.
I treat you as the woman my
master has chosen to court.
So please, do not start treating
me as a citizen of Illdoren.
I would never...
Well, you may have a point.
I'll be more careful.
Cersei...
Yes?
Are the memories of our homeland...
something you would rather forget?
Well... it's more like I don't remember,
anyway. And can't be bothered to.
Since I never intend on going back.
H-How could I, a retinue priest,
be so careless?!
I understand how you feel,
but you would've been stuck like
that unless someone said something.
While it's true that my
memories might be... hazy...
It looked like you'd mutter
to yourself for the rest of your life.
S-S-Say what?!
Just calm down, Malcius.
Could someone explain why
I'm on an errand
with the girl I was wrestling with?!
I might be willing to accompany
this barbarian girl
since I can't leave your side,
Lady Serafina, but...
Because you stink.
What did you just say?
Are you saying I s-s-stink?
Yes, you do.
I'm sure you haven't noticed yourself,
but it's a mixture of blood, sweat,
a bit sour, and some faint perfume.
I have to wonder how long
it's been since you last bathed.
Uh...
Well, it was four days before
Lady Serafina served as the vanguard,
and was captured the barbarians...
Over half a month?
Malcius... it's just... well...
There was never a good time...
and I do feel bad for
not saying anything.
Forgive me.
Right.
That said, I've worked up quite a
sweat over these last two or three days.
This might be perfect timing.
I'll keep my sword nearby,
just in case we need it.
I really doubt you need to worry about it.
This area around the mountain by the
village is Master Veor's territory,
so dragons don't come around here often.
E-Even if they're rare, you still bathe
in places dragons have been seen?
Well, anywhere else would
be actual dragon territory,
as I'm sure you saw in the western woods.
I want to go back west...
I'm sorry, Malcius.
But like I told you before, I don't
intend on leaving here any time soon.
I'd recommend cleaning up quickly.
You don't want to catch a chill.
Right.
Lady Serafina?
A campfire after a bath can be quite nice.
Cleaning off does lose its charm
if you're freezing from the water.
It's warm...
I think they're just about done.
Yes, it looks like it.
It's good...
I suppose it's time for
this great cleansing...
Gotta say, it's real good the blight
was purged as fast as it was.
If it's still in its cocoon,
the cleansing is easier to set up,
and easier to do!
I heard the new bride took it down.
Talk about bold. Couldn't be me!
I can't believe how much the
story has spread in one day...
Oh, we worked hard to make
it happen, believe me!
Come to think of it, Malcius landed
on your head, knocking you both out...
I-I'm not usually that careless!
I didn't have a helmet, either!
Besides, I dare you to find
anyone who doesn't relax
after slaying something like that!
I suppose you're right about that.
And while Illdoren was knocked
out, we were flying all around!
And now, I'm exhausted!
That sounds like quite the ordeal.
Thank you for your efforts.
Well, the truth is, I don't
really know what exhaustion is.
You see, Sera, because the Tefyu
are more like natural phenomenon,
their perception is bit
different from ours.
She might even have trouble
telling Cersei and Malcius apart.
That seems like more than "a bit."
What's it matter,
as long as I can tell the difference
between important people?
That's starting to sound
more like disinterest...
Here we are!
There it is.
What a mess...
What is this?
Wh-Wh-What the?
It's like it's been bleached...
This is... white dust?
The area where we fought the
Fiend has turned to dust.
Another effect of the blight.
The same way that we all have wills,
the earth, water, flame,
and wind do as well.
And while they're all similiar in nature,
there's one fundamental difference between
the will of living creatures
and any other kind....
When a life is depleted of willpower,
it simply never returns.
But for for everything else...
for nature itself, willpower stagnates,
grows corrupt, forgetting its
intended state, and turns to dust.
Or so I was told
by our resident Rijutsushi,
Karka Roth, several years ago.
Hello!
It sounded really convincing...
but it was all just second-hand knowledge?
Hey there!
I suppose I can go into
greater detail, then.
But first, I'd like to see the tool
of the fool who caused this mess.
Here it is.
Th-That's my scripture!
Give it back!
Thief...!
A rijutsu text, primarily focused
on converting things to light,
heat, and impact.
I thought as much.
Indeed. Completely lacking in artistry.
B-But it seemed dangerous
enough to do real damage
if one wasn't wearing armor...
It used enough of the land's willpower
to leave it in this state, after all.
There's no arguing against its potency.
But from our point of view,
the very idea of using rijutsu for
destruction is inherently crude.
Now, then, it's almost noon.
With weather this pleasant,
it should prove a nice
wake-up call, for the land.
What are those?
Catalysts. Brought in by
the different clans...
Offering earth, water,
fire, and wind catalysts
along with a prayer acts as an excitation
to help the land recall its true nature.
Let's begin.
In the name of the great spirits, we will
now perform the great cleansing.
Vesenem kehfem kehnakyahne fonehda.
Something about his words sounded older
than any language I'd ever heard,
as they echoed across the depleted earth.
Sesah mufeneh enim oyavee eewoo.
A call for purification,
passed down for countless millennia.
Vanoh oo oah vanokeh
effzoh keffay wekiyoh!
Chasing away calamity, purging blight...
A prayer to purify
all wickedness in creation.
A call for a great cleansing...
That should do.
What did you think, Sera?
Sera...?
Why are you crying?
That makes 30.
The idea of a Lavillant woman planting
trees would've been unheard of.
But it's not bad.
That said, I wasn't expecting
such a mystic ritual to be
followed by this kind of group work.
You look puzzled.
Veor? Well, I was just thinking
about how ordinary this all seems.
You're right. Healing a
forest takes ordinary work.
But if we don't attend to this ordinary
work, then the forest will be lost.
Which will cause trouble
for our children, grandchildren,
and future generations.
The sentiment that only
our individual concerns,
in the present, are what matter...
Is a rejection of our shared fate
is what gives rise to the blight.
Fiends are the avatars of
greed and self-interest.
In this current case, the willpower of
the land was being drained for the spell,
and after having become unstable,
the land, in return, drained the
caster of their memories and will.
It takes all that in return?
That sounds severe.
It certainly is.
Severe enough to wipe the memory and
personality of the one involved.
Then Malcius' memories being lost...
Yes, that was the cause.
I mentioned a bit about this earlier,
but this would normally be enough
to leave someone a shell...
Rarely is someone
lucky enough to be freed
before they are fully drained.
Such individuals are typically
said to have been cleansed.
Barbarian girl...
Your said your name was Malcius.
That's the name given to children
raised in the orphanage
attached to the
Order of Commoneras' Malcius Abbey.
I honestly think you're better
off forgetting what would've
led you to being taken in
by that country's orphanage
and what you went through there.
You should focus on
planting those saplings.
That's another kind of cleansing.
Translation: Lee Francis
Timing: Andy Ellis
Editing: Zachary Carlysle
Quality Control: Salem Alabanza
Translation Check: Sho Stifler
Say, Veor...
I think I know why you all consider
the blight so wretched, now.
I see.
And...
The east... the relationship between
the people here, and nature...
I think I understand what you're fighting,
and trying to accomplish, too.
I see.